rateitall.com 2001-06-03

# RateItAll - The Opinion Network

|    

| **Check out these popular ratings lists...**  
---  
  
The bottom line is that RateItAll will NOT release your personal information without your consent. 

Earning the trust of our users is one of RateItAll’s primary goals. We take your privacy very seriously, and we want you to feel absolutely comfortable using our site. Our Privacy Policy answers the following questions: 

  1. Are you certified by TRUSTe?
  2. What information do you collect, how is it collected and how do you use it?
  3. How is my privacy protected when I leave comments?
  4. How will I know if you change your privacy policy?
  5. What kind of security measures do you take?
  6. What are the limits of your Privacy Policy?
  7. How do I opt-out of your communication lists?
  8. How can I change my personal information?
  9. What if I have more questions?
  10. How can I be sure that you adhere to your Privacy Policy?

|  **1\. Are you certified by TRUSTe?**  
---  
Yes! RateItAll is certified by TRUSTe as follows: 

This confirms that RateItAll is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. Because this Web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. By displaying the TRUSTe trustmark, this Web site has agreed to notify you of: 

  1. What personally identifiable information of yours or third party personally identification is collected from you through the web site 
  2. The organization collecting the information 
  3. How the information is used 
  4. With whom the information may be shared 
  5. What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information 
  6. The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under RateItAll's control 
  7. How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information. 

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact Craig Hughes by sending an e-mail to craig@rateitall.com. If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact [TRUSTe](http://www.truste.org/users/users_watchdog.html). TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with the Web site to resolve your concerns. [](http://www.truste.org/validate/6075)   
  
**2\. What information do you collect, how is it collected and how do you use it?**  
Anyone can visit our site free of charge. You are welcome to browse our ratings lists and read comments without ever giving us your individual information. But we do need to gather some information about users who wish to submit ratings and comments. We collect information in two ways: directly from you and through the use of "cookies".

First, if you want to rate something, we will ask you to provide some personal information. If you have already registered, you know that the information we require is very basic: your e-mail address, a password, your gender, the year you were born, and where you are from. We collect that demographic information so that our users can filter the ratings lists by the age, gender, (and - coming soon - location), of the people who submitted the ratings. So, for instance, our users can ask to see a ratings list of "Current Rock & Pop CDs" that only reflects the opinions of males between the ages of 19-25.

One of the reasons we ask for your e-mail address is so that we can communicate with you and possibly send you the latest information about RateItAll. You can opt-out of receiving correspondence from us by selecting that option when you register. If you don't want to hear from us, we promise to leave you alone! Many of our members, however, enjoy getting news from us and being informed of special promotions or opportunities (which may include an opportunity to be paid for participating in on-line focus groups).

Second, when you register with RateItAll, a "cookie" may be placed on your computer. Cookies are bits of information that a web site places on your computer's hard drive for record-keeping and activity-tracking purposes. Cookies cannot be used to learn your identity unless you have previously provided that information to that web site or your web browser automatically provides that information. Other web sites, including some of our advertisers, may also place cookies on your hard drive, but if you have not previously provided your identity to the web site and your browser does not automatically provide your identity, an advertiser will not be able to use a cookie to learn your identity.

In conjunction with the registration information you provide, cookies help us recognize you when you return to the site, and they let you avoid having to log-in each time you visit. In addition, it allows us to do other things that increase the usefulness of the site. This includes personalizing our service so the content we show you better matches your interests. Eventually our system will be able to make guesses about your interests based on the parts of the site you visit, the ratings you submit, and the demographic information you give us when you register. 

We also collect log files that identify information such as IP address, browser type, domain name, referral URL, country of origin, pages visited, entry points, and exit points, but we do NOT link those files to personally identifying information.

We plan that, from time to time, we will provide certain companies (like our advertisers) with aggregated user information, but this will **NOT** contain any individual information. We will **NOT** give advertisers or anyone else personal information about you without your specific authorization to do so, except as specifically described in this Privacy Policy. While we don't do it now, we expect that one day other businesses may ask us to do things like "broker" on-line focus groups, in which we may invite some users to participate (if they have chosen to be notified of those opportunities).

If you elect to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site (by clicking the link that says "Invite a friend to rate!"), we will ask you for the friend's name and e-mail address. RateItAll will automatically send the friend a one-time e-mail inviting them to visit the site. RateItAll stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time e-mail. The friend may contact us to request the removal of this information from our database.

Our site occasionally requests information from users via surveys or sweepstakes. Participation in these surveys or sweepstakes is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Information requested may include contact info (like name and shipping address) and demographic information (such as zip code, age level). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving your use and satisfaction of this site.

From time to time we create co-branded or private label versions of our web site for third parties. A co-branded or private label version of our web site will bear the trademark or service mark, and perhaps the "look and feel", of the third party sponsor ("Co-Brand Sponsor") whose link brought you to our site. Personal information collected during the registration process from users of co-branded and private label versions of our web site will be shared with the relevant Co-Brand Sponsor. We require that each Co-Brand Sponsor commit to us that its collection and use of personal information shall be no less protective of users' privacy than permitted by this Privacy Policy, as modified from time to time. However, while we strive to associate with other businesses who value your privacy, we are not responsible for the privacy practices of the Co-Brand Sponsors.  You may wish to review those sites' privacy policies. 

Of course, notwithstanding anything in this policy to the contrary, we will provide personal information if we are or believe that we are legally required to do so pursuant to a subpoena, warrant, other legal method or applicable law.

 **3\. How is my privacy protected when I leave comments?**  
One of the great features of RateItAll is that we allow you, as a user, to leave comments - not just ratings - so you can explain your opinions in some detail. Please remember that when you post your comments they are publicly available, so you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose anything personal about yourself. This includes your e-mail address. Many of our users like to leave their e-mail addresses with their comments. That way others can e-mail them if they want to discuss the comment. You should realize that you are not obligated to attach your email address.  
  
 **4\. How will I know if you change your privacy policy?**  
This privacy policy may be revised over time as new features are added to the Web site. We will post those changes prominently so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and whether we will disclose it to anyone. If we are going to use your personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify you via e-mail. You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in this different manner. In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our web site notifying users of the change. In some cases where we post the notice we will also e-mail users, who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices.  
  
 **5\. What kind of security measures do you take?**  
Any information you provide, other than information you chose to provide and make publicly available in your posts, is maintained and accessible only by us, and only by those of our employees with a need to have access to such information in the performance of their work. This site has instituted commercially reasonable security measures to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control or in our possession. All data stores are held behind a commercial grade firewall and are only enabled through an encrypted multi-protocol pipe. All open ports and protocols have been closed on the Web servers excluding http, https, and outbound smtp mail. In addition, all user accounts are restricted to specific algorithms noting both length and complexity. Unfortunately, data transmission over the Internet can not be guaranteed to be totally secure. Additionally, we use an outside company to display ads on our site. These ads may contain cookies. While we use cookies in other parts of our Web site, cookies received with banner ads are collected by our ad company, and we do not have access to this information. Therefore, although we take measures, such as those described in this Privacy Policy, to protect your personal information, we can not warrant the security of information that you provide. Accordingly, you agree that you are providing such information at your own risk.  
  
 **6\. What are the limits of your Privacy Policy?**  
The RateItAll Web site contains hyperlinks and advertisements that, if activated in the manner provided by your browser, will cause your browser to access and display the contents of other Web sites. RateItAll does not control or have any knowledge concerning the provisions of the privacy policies, if any, of those sites. Accordingly, RateItAll is not responsible for the privacy practices or any of the content of those Web sites and RateitAll’s Privacy Policy does not apply to those other sites. If you choose to activate a hyperlink to another Web site, you do so at your own risk and you may wish to review that site’s privacy policy.  
  
 **7\. How do I opt-out of your communication lists?**  
As mentioned previously, RateItAll provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us and our partners during the registration process. Users can also remove themselves from our e-mailing list by writing to us at info@rateitall.com.  
  
 **8\. How can I change my personal information?**  
Users can modify their personal information by sending an email to info@rateitall.com.  
  
 **9\. What if I have more questions?**  
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, please send an e-mail to info@rateitall.com. You may also contact RateItAll at 415-575-9616 or send a letter to RateItAll.com, Inc., 417 14th St., San Francisco, CA, 94109.  
  
 **10\. How can I be sure that you adhere to your Privacy Policy?**  
If for any reason you believe that RateItAll has not adhered to the principles contained in this Privacy Policy, please notify us at info@rateitall.com. We will do our best to address your concerns and to confirm and correct the problem promptly.  
  
_Acceptance of Terms._

By using this site you acknowledge and agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. If you disagree with any term or condition in this Privacy Policy, you must not use our site.
